

SENIOR SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

acordmike@gmail.com 1-920-224-4584 https://www.mikeacord.com

Seasoned application developer and solutions consultant with over 14 years of experience in designing, developing, and implementing database and web applications using Microsoft technologies. Specialties include C#, ASP.Net MVC, SQL Server development and administration and SharePoint deployment, development and administration.

SKILLS

WEB JAVASCRIPT HTML 5 CSS LAMP MVC REST CSS

JAVASCRIPT ANGULAR.JS JQUERY BACKBONE.JS

DATABASE SQL SERVER TSQL INTEGRATION SERVICES ANALYSIS SERVICES REPORTING SERVICES

CLOUD AZURE

PROJECT AGILE TFS

DEVOPS TFS TEAM CITY OCTOPUS DEPLOY

SHAREPOINT ADMINISTRATION DEVELOPMENT OFFICE 365

EMPLOYMENT

Senior Solutions Architect, Consultant, Omni Resources

2012-07 — Present

Senior Microsoft Architect, building solutions for clients

- Led team creating web-based report designer and high-performance report execution engine for a student management system
- Worked on team developing a dealer showcase website in Azure using ASP.Net MVC, web services and Backbone.JS
- Developed new data warehouse for an insurance company using SQL Server, AWS and Redshift
- Developed a flexible interview building and reporting application for a health outcome reporting company
- Managed and administrated internal systems and applications

Agile C# DevOps Javascript ASP.Net MVC SQL Server Analysis Services Integration Services SharePoint Azure Business Intelligence Office365 TFS Administration

SharePoint/Business Intelligence Technical Lead / Consultant,

2008-06 — 2012-06

Heartland Business Systems (Avastone)

Designed and developed custom .Net, Business Intelligence and SharePoint solutions for businesses, managed technical consulting team

- Developed school teacher evaluation system in SharePoint, .Net and javascript
- Created health reporting and analytics system in ASP.Net MVC
- Designed and created school district website in SharePoint
- Developed new product workflow application in InfoPath
- Designed and developed a data warehouse on SQL Server database and Analysis Services
- Implemented numerous SharePoint installations, upgrades and custom development projects

C# Javascript ASP.Net MVC SQL Server Analysis Services Integration Services Sharepoint Business Intelligence

Business Intelligence Consultant, Fujitsu Consulting

2006-08 — 2008-04

Senior BI Consultant building data integration solutions

- Designed and developed data migration strategy from legacy system using Integration Services
- Created real-time data integration from new web application back to legacy mainframe
- Developed reporting services reports

SSIS SQL Server ASP.Net C# Reporting Services

Business Intelligence Consultant, Compuware

2005-05 — 2006-07

SQL Server development consulting

- Developed and optimized SQL Server applications
 Developed bill of materials past reporting applications
- Developed bill of materials cost reporting application in MS Access
 Developed Crystal Paperts
- Developed Crystal Reports

SQL Server MS Access Crystal Reports

Systems Analyst, DRS Power & Control Technologies

2001-08 — 2005-08

Internal application development and support

- Gathered and analyzed business requirements
- Used application development methodologies to create internal business applications
 Led cross-functional multi-site teams to facilitate and improve business processes
- Led cross-functional, multi-site teams to facilitate and improve business processes
- Created an Operational Data Store from mainframe data and Crystal Reports to the analyze data
 SQL Server DTS ASP VB.Net

SQL Server D13 A3F VB.Net

EDUCATION

MS in Management-Electronic Business, University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee

2002-08 — 2003-12

BS in Business and Computer Systems, International Business,
Milwaukee School of Engineering